Guide to the Salisbury Family Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Edward Elbridge Salisbury Papers, 1836-1904; Series I; (5 boxes, 1 folio)
  - Correspondence
    - Salisbury, Stephen (1798-1884), 1844-1884 (Box 3, Folder 174)
    - Salisbury, Stephen (1835-1905), 1880-1894 (Box 3, Folder 175)
    - Salisbury, Waldo, 1877 (Box 3, Folder 176)
    - Schele deVere, Maximilian, 1846-1877 (Box 3, Folder 177)
    - Settle, William, 1873 (Box 3, Folder 178)
    - Seymour, Thomas Day, 1884-1895 (Box 3, Folder 179)
    - Short, Charles, 1874 (Box 3, Folder 180)
    - Silliman, Benjamin, 1877-1882 (Box 3, Folder 181)
    - Silliman, Benjamin Douglas, 1896 (Box 3, Folder 182)
    - Singleton, Esther, 1901 (Box 3, Folder 183)
    - Smith, Joel Sumner, 1892 (Box 3, Folder 184)
    - Sohier, William Davies, 1829-1860 (Box 3, Folder 185)
    - Starr, Nathaniel Winthrop, 1883 (Box 3, Folder 186)
    - Steitz, Anna (de Wette), 1875 (Box 3, Folder 187)
    - Stiles, Henry R., 1893 (Box 3, Folder 188)
    - Stillé, Alfred, 1887-1888 (Box 3, Folder 189)
    - Stoeckel, Gustave Jacob, 1889 (Box 3, Folder 190)
    - Tappan, F.H., 1895 (Box 3, Folder 191)
    - Tappan, John, 1877 (Box 3, Folder 192)
    - Thacher, Thomas Anthony, 1866-1886 (Box 3, Folder 193)
    - Thompson, Frederick D., 1892 (Box 3, Folder 194)
    - Ticknor, George, 1870 (Box 3, Folder 195)
    - Tracy, Charles, 1880 (Box 3, Folder 196)
    - Train, Abner Leavenworth, n.y. (Box 3, Folder 197)
    - Trumbull, James Hammond, 1874-1888 (Box 3, Folder 198)
    - Tyler, Moses Coit, 1878-1897 (Box 3, Folder 199)
    - Van Name, Addison, 1870-1895 (Box 3, Folder 200)
    - Vespre, Francis, 1837 (Box 3, Folder 201)
    - Waite, Morrison Remick, 1881-1885 (Box 4, Folder 202)
    - Walker, George Leon, 1889-1891 (Box 4, Folder 203)
    - Wally, Henshaw B., 1883 (Box 4, Folder 204)
    - Ward, William Hayes, 1898 (Box 4, Folder 205)
    - Ware, William Robert, 1889 (Box 4, Folder 206)
    - Washington, Booker Taliaferro, 1901, 1904 (Box 4, Folder 207)
    - Weber, Prof., 1843 (Box 4, Folder 208)
    - Weir, John Ferguson, 1871-1895 (Box 4, Folder 209)
    - Wetmore, George Peabody, 1893 (Box 4, Folder 210)
    - Wheeler, Arthur Martin, 1877-1888 (Box 4, Folder 211)
    - White, Henry, 1873 (Box 4, Folder 212)
    - White, James T. and Co., 1896 (Box 4, Folder 213)
    - Whitney, Elizabeth B., [1895?] (Box 4, Folder 214)
    - Whitney, William Dwight, 1851-1893 (Box 4, Folder 215)
    - Willcox, David, 1893 (Box 4, Folder 216)
    - Winslow, William Copley, 1886 (Box 4, Folder 217)
    - Winsor, Justin, 1886 (Box 4, Folder 218)
    - Winthrop, Charles Archibald, 1880 (Box 4, Folder 219)
    - Winthrop, Robert Charles (1809-1894), 1890 (Box 4, Folder 220)
    - Winthrop, Robert Charles (1834-1905), 1890 (Box 4, Folder 221)
    - Woodbridge, William Channing, 1844 (Box 4, Folder 222)
    - Woodbury, Charles, 1896 (Box 4, Folder 223)
    - Woolsey, Elizabeth Martha (Salisbury), 1845-1846 (Box 4, Folder 224)
    - Woolsey, Theodore Dwight, 1845-1886, undated (Box 4, Folder 225)
    - Young, Mason, 1877 (Box 4, Folder 226)
    - Unidentified (Box 4, Folder 227)
    - Correspondence scrapbook re: Salisbury Collection in Yale University Library (Box 4, Folder 228)
  - Writings
    - notes on a Journey to the South from New Haven, Conn., 1831 May 4 (Box 4, Folder 229)
    - "On Classical and Modern Literature", 1831 June 22 (Box 4, Folder 230)
    - "The Perversion of Feelings", 1834 June (Box 4, Folder 231)
    - Address on religion and society, 1834 December (Box 4, Folder 232)
    - Address regarding rebuilding of Yale campus, [ca. 1884-1886?] (Box 4, Folder 233)
    - A Genealogical Study on the Descent of John Salisbury of Boston, 1689-1702, 1900 (Box 4, Folder 234)
    - Essay on formation of intellectual character, undated (Box 4, Folder 235)
    - On the usage of the leading temporal forms in the Semitish conjugation, undated (Box 4, Folder 236)
    - Essay on polygamy, undated (Box 4, Folder 237)
    - Essay on the ten commandments, undated (Box 4, Folder 238)
    - Essay on Arabian history, undated (Box 4, Folder 239)
    - "The Knowledge of a future state among the Hebrews between the time of Moses and the Captivity", undated (Box 4, Folder 240)
    - "The expectation of the apostles relative to the time of the day of judgement", undated (Box 4, Folder 241)
    - "The influence of the spirit of Christianity on the discovery of truth", undated (Box 4, Folder 242)
    - Sermon: Matthew 26:36-44, undated (Box 4, Folder 243)
    - Sermon: II Timothy 3:6 (Box 4, Folder 244)
    - Sermon: I John 4:18 (Box 4, Folder 245)
    - Miscellaneous notes and fragments (Box 4, Folder 246)
    - Journal of Travels in Europe, 1836 June 10 - 1839 August 6 (Box 5, Folder 247-251)
    - Ms notes of Bopp's published Interpretation of the Fragments by Lassen in Anthologia Sanscritta 76pp., 1839 (Box 6, Folder 252)
    - notes of lectures by Professor Bopp on Greek and Latin Etymology with Reference to the Sanscrit, 1839 (Box 6, Folder 253)
    - noten zu Vorträgen des Herrn Prof. Bopp über Sansc. - Gram. u einige Gesänge des Nalus, 1838-1839 (Box 6, Folder 254)
    - noten zu Vorträgen des Herrn Prof. Bopp über das Diluvium etc. und den Hitopadesa, 1838-1839 (Box 6, Folder 255)
    - notes on Arabic and Semitic Culture and History (Box 6, Folder 256)
  - Special Files
    - Legal Documents and Financial Papers (Box 6, Folder 257-259)
    - Documents and Copies of Documents relative to the Salisbury Professorship (Box 6, Folder 260)
    - William Dwight Whitney Memorial Material (Printed) (Box 6, Folder 261)
    - Diploma from Harvard University, 1886
      General note
      See: Folio 24
- Genealogies, Series II
  Scope and Contents
  Series II, Genealogies, also includes some oversize materials in boxes 16-23 which are shelved at the end of the collection. A separate listing for oversize materials is on page 25.
  - Scrapbooks
    - Diodati genealogy (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Griswold genealogy (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Salisbury "Family Memorials" (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - McCurdy "Family Histories and Genealogies" (Box 8a, Folder 4)
    - McCurdy "Family Histories and Genealogies" (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Extracts copied from genealogies, clippings, etc. (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous genealogical material (Box 10, Folder 7-9)
- Family Papers, 1753-1865; Series III; (4 boxes)
  - Breese, Elizabeth -- Diary fragments, 1806-1824 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Chevalier, Peter -- ALS to Mrs. Shippen, 1772 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Gerry, Thomas -- ALS to Martha Salisbury, 1759 October 1 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Quincy, Edmund -- Two letters from, 1756, 1757 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Salisbury, Abigail Breese (Correspondence of)
    - Alcott, A. May, [1825] (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Austin, Sarah, 1848, 1861 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Bayard, A.M., undated (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Breese, Catherine Hallett, 1844 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Breese, F.H., 1851 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Breese, Fanny [Francis Helen?], 1843 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Breese, Helen, 1842 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Breese, Samuel, 1855 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Breese, Samuel Sidney, 1844-1848 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Breisel, J. Salisbury, 1847 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Browne, Mary Andrews, undated (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Cleveland, Abby (Salisbury), [ca. 1804 1808] (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Cutler, Francis Gallagher, 1858-1859, undated (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Davenport, Elizabeth Sewall Leverett, 1848 (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Davis, Mary D., 1864 (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Emerson, G.B., 1828 (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - Gallagher, Joseph Steele, 1858 (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - Graves, Catherine Hallett Breese, 1859, 1863 (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - Hazard, Samuel, 1799,1854-1855 (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - Higginson, E., 1826, 1829 (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - Higginson, Louise, 1834, undated (Box 11, Folder 25)
    - Higginson, M.L., 1826 (Box 11, Folder 26)
    - Hodge, Dr. [underline], 1861 (Box 11, Folder 27)
    - Johnson, Sarah W., undated (Box 11, Folder 28)
    - Joy, B., 1826-1836, undated (Box 11, Folder 29)
    - Keith, E.S., [1840] (Box 11, Folder 30)
    - Lind, Susan W., 1843-1852 (Box 11, Folder 31)
    - McClellan, R.L., 1864 (Box 11, Folder 32)
    - Morse, Richard Cary, 1857, 1861 (Box 11, Folder 33)
    - Morse, Samuel Finley Breese, 1838-1855 (Box 11, Folder 34)
    - Morse, Sidney Edwards, 1858-1861 (Box 11, Folder 35)
    - Norton, E.C., 1860 (Box 11, Folder 36)
    - Norton, John T., 1860 (Box 11, Folder 37)
    - Packard, Susan Breese Gallagher, 1861-1865 (Box 11, Folder 38)
    - Platt, Sarah, 1855 (Box 11, Folder 39)
    - Pond, Enoch, 1850 (Box 11, Folder 40)
    - Phillips, Martha S., 1829 (Box 11, Folder 41)
    - Proal, Susan B., 1861 (Box 11, Folder 42)
    - Phillips, Rebecca Waldo (Salisbury), [pre-1805?]-1827 (Box 11, Folder 43)
    - Salisbury, Abigail Breese (Correspondence of) (Box 11, Folder 43)
    - Quincy, Anna, 1849 (Box 11, Folder 43a)
    - Redfield, George Snowden, 1863 (Box 11, Folder 44)
    - Rockwood, A.A., 1861 (Box 11, Folder 45)
    - Salisbury, Abigail Salisbury Phillips, 1838-1842 (Box 11, Folder 45a)
    - Salisbury, Edward Elbridge, 1833-1843 (Box 11, Folder 45b)
    - Salisbury, Elizabeth Tuckerman, 1829-1833 (Box 11, Folder 46)
    - Salisbury, Nancy, 1849 (Box 11, Folder 47)
    - Salisbury, Rebecca, 1848, 1855 (Box 11, Folder 48)
    - Salisbury, Stephen, Jr., 1826, 1829 (Box 11, Folder 49)
    - Sands, Catherine Livingston, 1848 (Box 11, Folder 50)
    - Sands, Elizabeth, 1848, 1861 (Box 11, Folder 51)
    - Smith, Edward, 1861 (Box 11, Folder 52)
    - Snow, S.M., [1826?] (Box 11, Folder 53)
    - Snow, R.W., 1826-1844 (Box 11, Folder 54)
    - Snowden, Arthur Henry, 1860 (Box 11, Folder 55)
    - Snowden, Ebenezer Hazard, 1848 (Box 11, Folder 56)
    - Snowden, Robert Bayard, 1864 (Box 11, Folder 57)
    - Snowden, Samuel Breese, 1824, 1851 (Box 11, Folder 58)
    - Snowden, Samuel Finley, 1842 (Box 11, Folder 59)
    - Snowden, Susan Bayard, 1842, 1848 (Box 11, Folder 60)
    - Sohier, William Davies, 1842 (Box 11, Folder 60a)
    - Stevens, Breese, 1861 (Box 11, Folder 61)
    - Stevens, Elizabeth, 1848-1863 (Box 11, Folder 62)
    - Stoddard, D.J., 1850 (Box 11, Folder 63)
    - Tappen, Frances, 1861 (Box 11, Folder 64)
    - Tappan, John, 1835-1855 (Box 11, Folder 65)
    - Vermilye, Elizabeth Breese, 1848, 1859 (Box 11, Folder 66)
    - Walker, Sarah Ann, 1849 (Box 11, Folder 67)
    - Walker, Thomas Read, 1857 (Box 11, Folder 68)
    - Walley, S.H., 1826 (Box 11, Folder 69)
    - Wayland, H.L., 1861 (Box 11, Folder 70)
    - Wisner, B.B., 1826 (Box 11, Folder 71)
    - Woolsey, Elizabeth Martha Salisbury, 1833-1846 (Box 11, Folder 71a)
    - Woolsey, Theodore Dwight, 1846 (Box 11, Folder 71b)
    - Miscellaneous and Unidentified correspondence, 1857, undated (Box 11, Folder 72)
    - Commonplace Book (notes from Mosheim's Church History), 1792 (Box 11, Folder 73)
    - Drawings (Box 11, Folder 74)
    - Salisbury, Josiah (1734-1761) Business letters received, 1756-1760 (Box 11, Folder 75)
  - Salisbury, Josiah (1781-1826) (Correspondence of)
    - [note from E.E. Salisbury], 1880 March 15 (Box 11, Folder 76)
    - Anderson, R., 1825 (Box 11, Folder 77)
    - Blanchard, Elizabeth, 1819 (Box 11, Folder 78)
    - Breese, Arthur, 1821-1825 (Box 11, Folder 79)
    - Breese, Elizabeth, 1810, 1825 (Box 12, Folder 80)
    - Breese, Samuel Livingston, 1821 (Box 12, Folder 81)
    - Breese, Samuel Sidney, 1817-1823, undated (Box 12, Folder 82)
    - Breese, Sidney, 1821 (Box 12, Folder 83)
  - Salisbury, Josiah (Correspondence of)
    - Brooks, C., 1819 (Box 12, Folder 84)
    - Codman, John, 1824 (Box 12, Folder 85)
    - Dwight, Louis, 1825 (Box 12, Folder 86)
    - Farlan, Patrick M., 1825 (Box 12, Folder 87Fa)
    - Frothingham, N.L., 1823 (Box 12, Folder 88)
    - Gallison, J., 1819 (Box 12, Folder 89)
    - Green, Benjamin, 1801, 1803 (Box 12, Folder 90)
    - Hazard, Ebenezer, 1815 (Box 12, Folder 91)
    - Hazard, Erskine, 1820 (Box 12, Folder 92)
    - Henry, Symmes C., 1820 (Box 12, Folder 93)
    - Higginson, Stephen, 1801-1802, 1822 (Box 12, Folder 94)
    - Gomes, H., 1824 (Box 12, Folder 95)
    - Jenks, William, 1822 (Box 12, Folder 96)
    - Leverett, John, 1814-1815 (Box 12, Folder 97)
    - Miller, Samuel, 1809,1820 (Box 12, Folder 98)
    - Morse, J., 1815, 1819 (Box 12, Folder 99)
    - Rockwood, Daniel, 1819 (Box 12, Folder 100)
    - Rockwood, E.B., 1819-1820 (Box 12, Folder 101)
    - Rockwood, Ebenezer, 1825 (Box 12, Folder 102)
    - Ropes, William, 1824 (Box 12, Folder 103)
    - Salisbury, Abigail Breese, 1812-1817 (Box 12, Folder 104)
    - Salisbury, Rebecca, 1796-1802 (Box 12, Folder 105)
    - Salisbury, Samuel, 1800-1816 (Box 12, Folder 106)
    - Salisbury, Samuel, Jr., 1799, 1812 (Box 12, Folder 107)
    - Salisbury, Stephen, 1794-1826 (Box 12, Folder 108-117)
    - Salisbury, Stephen, Jr., 1819-1826 (Box 13, Folder 118)
    - Sewall, S., 1823 (Box 13, Folder 119)
    - Snowden, S.F., 1824 (Box 13, Folder 120)
    - Storrs, R.L., 1823 (Box 13, Folder 121)
    - Stuart, Moses, 1815, undated (Box 13, Folder 122)
    - Thacher, P.D., 1823 (Box 13, Folder 123)
    - Waldo, Daniel, 1819, 1821 (Box 13, Folder 124)
    - Waldo, Sarah (and Rebecca), 1819 (Box 13, Folder 125)
    - Walley, S.H., [1820?] (Box 13, Folder 126)
    - Wisner, B.B., 1822-1825, undated (Box 13, Folder 127)
    - Woods, Leonard, 1819-1821 (Box 13, Folder 128)
    - Miscellaneous and unidentified, 1819-1825 (Box 13, Folder 129)
    - notes of foreign travel, 1800-1802 (Box 13, Folder 130)
    - Sermon fragments (Box 13, Folder 131)
  - Salisbury, Martha -- Drawing (Box 13, Folder 132)
  - Salisbury, Samuel -- Correspondence, 1818 (Box 13, Folder 133)
  - Salisbury, Samuel and Stephen, 1771-1787, 1789-1806 (Box 13, Folder 133-145)
  - Sewall, Joseph -- Letter from, 1753 (Box 13, Folder 146)
  - Tappen, John -- Letter from, 1818 (Box 13, Folder 147)
  - Waldo, Sarah -- Letter from, 1826 (Box 13, Folder 148)
  - Salisbury Family -- Miscellaneous (Box 13, Folder 149)
  - Salisbury, Rebecca -- 6 scrapbooks containing miscellaneous writings and clippings - mainly on the subject of numismatics (Box 14, Folder 150)
  - Salisbury, Edward Elbridge -- Family-memorials. A series of genealogical and biographical monographs on the families of Salisbury, Aldworth-Elbridge, Sewall, Pyldren-Dummer, Walley, Quincy, Gookin, Wendell, Breese, Chevalier-Anderson, and Phillips. With fifteen pedigrees and an appendix. New Haven, Privately Printed, 1885. 696 p. Flyleaf inscription: Mary S. Gillette in memory of the author 1903 Mar; from Evelyn McCurdy Salisbury. Half-title: In one volume-second half. (Box 15, Folder 150)
  - Three volumes of engravings (portraits, architectural and landscape scenes). Added 1979 Nov.
    See: boxes 21-23
- Oversize Materials
  - From Series II
    - Memorial volume on Judge McCurdy [scrapbook] (Box 16)
    - Scrapbook of correspondence and documents pertaining to Salisbury Family genealogy, [added 1972 Feb] (Box 17)
    - "Genealogical Collections Chester Correspondence" (Box 18)
    - "Somerby Collection of Salisbury Pedigrees" (Box 19)
    - "Genealogical Collections" [volumes 1 and 2] (Box 20)
  - From Series III
    - Engravings [three volumes of portraits, architectural and landscape scenes] (Box 21)
    - Engravings [three volumes of portraits, architectural and landscape scenes] (Box 22)
    - Engravings [three volumes of portraits, architectural and landscape scenes] (Box 23)
  - From Series I
    - Diploma from Harvard University, 1886 (Box 24)